Sharvika Nitin Kulkarni

5050 E Garford Street, Long Beach, CA 90815

J +1 562-713-9855 ■ sharvika.kulkarni05@gmail.com in LinkedIn Github

Summary

Full Stack Developer with 3 years of experience, excelling in object-oriented design and web development across telecom, finance and ecommerce sectors. Proven capabilities in Backend Development, Databse management, Automation Testing and Machine learning, with a notable ability to craft scalable web solutions and enhance user engagement through strategic improvements.

Education

California State University Long Beach

Aug 2019 - May 2024

Long Beach, CA

Masters of Science, Computer Science: CGPA - 3.7/4.0

Aug 2015 - May 2019

University of Pune

Bachelor of Engineering, Computer Engineering: CGPA - 8.0/10.0

Pune, IND

Technical Skills

Languages: Java, Javascript, Python, SQL

Web technologies/Frameworks: Spring, SpringBoot, REST, React, MVC, Microservices architecture, HTML/HTML5. CSS/CSS3.

Bootstrap, Angular, Node.is, Express.is, MongoDB, MERN Stack, Hibernate ORM

Database: MySQL, PL/SQL, PostgreSQL, NoSQL(Cassandra, Elasticsearch), Amazon RDS

Tools/Technologies: AWS Lambda, AWS API Gateway, AWS EC2, Selenium, JUnit, Selenium Webdriver, Postman, Github, Gitlab,

JIRA, Kibana, Jenkins

Machine Learning: Scikit-learn, K-means clustering, Naïve Bayes, Regularized Logistic Regression, Tableau, Numpy, Pandas, Tensorflow Others: Data Structures & Algorithms, Object Oriented Design, Problem Solving, Debugging & Testing, API development, Artificial Intelligence, Agile Development

Experience

Institutional Research & Analytics, CSULB

Jan 2023 - Aug 2023

Software Engineer - Part time

Long Beach, CA

- Created Tableau visualizations and dashboard reports to analyze CSULB student data and provide insights to stakeholders, reducing data access time by 60% for campus administrators.
- Engineered stored procedures and CRUD operations using SQL queries, streamlining the extraction and consolidation of financial aid data for approximately 20,000 students leading to optimization of report generation time and efficiency.
- Led the migration of database systems to Amazon RDS, ensuring robust and scalable management of financial aid data, coupled with AWS Lambda for serverless backend operations, significantly enhancing system efficiency and reducing operational cost.

Tata Consultancy Services

Apr 2021 - Jun 2022

Software Engineer

- Mumbai. IND
- Restructured API endpoints for a react based frontend web application, implementing caching for efficient data retrieval, and optimizing query execution, achieved a 25% reduction in server load and a 40% improvement in response times, enabling the e-commerce platform to accommodate 50% more concurrent users.
- Utilized Hibernate ORM to optimize database queries, exemplified by a streamlined product search feature that cut search times by 15%, enhancing the efficiency of product discovery process.
- Implemented a Spring Boot/MVC-based Order Tracking System with real-time updates and RESTful API integration, boosting customer satisfaction.
- Leveraged AWS cloud services, including AWS Lambda, API Gateway, and EC2, to architect scalable and secure microservices solutions, reducing infrastructure costs by 17%.
- Ensured robustness and reliability of new features and optimizations through comprehensive JUnit testing, systematically validating functionality and streamlining issue detection and resolution

Amdocs DVCI

Jun 2019 - Dec 2020

Pune, IND

Software Engineer

- Developed mobile flashcards using React, featuring responsive design and dynamic content rendering to showcase device details, and integrated it with a Java-based backend through RESTful APIs, ensuring dynamic data retrieval for continuously updated and accurate mobile flashcard content.
- · Led the creation of comprehensive test plans, incorporating Postman to efficiently perform automation testing of APIs and web services, reducing load testing time by 20% and achieving wider test coverage. This integration was seamlessly woven into our Jenkins CI/CD pipeline, resulting in a remarkable 30% reduction in test execution time, enhancing development workflow speed and efficiency.
- · Worked closely with the SCRUM for EPC micro releases and designed test scenarios, created test cases based on client requirements using HP Quality Center and tracked bug reports using Jenkins later migrating to JIRA.

FinIQ Consultancy India Pvt Ltd

May 2018 - Jun 2018

Full Stack Developer Intern

Nashik, IND

• Gained hands-on experience with the MERN stack by developing a payroll processing application, managing MongoDB data layers and creating a React-based user-friendly dashboard for efficient HR management.

Digital Impact Square, A TCS Foundation

Dec 2017 - Dec 2017 Nashik, IND

Software Engineer Intern

• Developed Naïve Bayes and Regularized Logistic Regression classifiers using Scikit-learn in Python, and applied K-means clustering to analyze 18 years of child abuse data, enhancing trend analysis and pattern recognition.